Minh Le | Curriculum Vitae

5 Aggie Village Apt B, Logan Utah 84341

I am a researcher in Computer Science at Utah State University. My research focus on opening the possibilities of applying mobile opportunistic networks to the extreme cases like disaster areas or battlefields with respect to trust, high performance and energy preservation. In software industry, I have totally 8 year experience in software design and development that made me professional in windows, web and mobile platforms and technologies.

Education

Utah State University

Advanced Software System Lab, Department of Computer Science

Logan, Utah 2015-Now

Konkuk University

Advanced Grid Computing, Department of Advanced Fusion Technology

Seoul, South Korea 2008–2010

Hanoi University of Technology

Department of Software Engineering

Hanoi, Vietnam 2001–2006

Notable Research Projects....

Service Market Middleware

A novel edge computing system architecture that uses an edge server to enable plug-and-play participation of arbitrary, off-the-shelf mobile devices, both stationary and on the move, to deliver failure-resistant and efficient applications.

o Effective Mobile Middleware for Remote Execution

My research focus on designing a comprehensive middleware for job remote executions on mobile opportunistic networks. The middleware enables job to be dispatched from any device within the network to the others, then selects an appropriate number of nearby devices by our selection algorithm for the execution. The POC implementation illustrates the capability of our middleware in reality with performance increased to 70% and 50% of energy conserved.

SensorBridge

Developed SensorBridge: a system extending message-oriented middleware to easily integrate with heterogeneous Wireless sensor networks. SensorBridge is adaptive with most of the sensor types, applicable for web and 3D virtualization systems.

Conference Papers....

- o Minh Le, Zheng Song, Eli Tilevich, Young-Woo Kwon, *Reliable and Efficient Mobile Edge Computing in Highly Dynamic and Volatile Environments*, ICFEC 2017 (Submitted)
- Minh Le, Young-Woo Kwon, Utilizing Nearby Computing Resources for Resource-Limited Mobile Devices, SAC 2017
- o Minh Le, Kim Dong-Wook, Jeong Karpjoo, Message delivery system for collaborative USN, IIWAS 2009
- o Minh Le, Sang Boem Lim, Jung-Hun Woo, HyungSeok Kim, A Data Transferring Model for Micro-scale Urban Air Quality Management System, NISS 2009
- o Jung-Hun Woo, Sang Boem Lim, Karpjoo Jeong, Minh Le, HyungSeok Kim, Jae-Jin Kim, Jonghyun Lee,

Previous Employment

NSoft Inc. Seoul, South Korea

Senior Software Developer

2012 - 2015

Developed an online publishing toolkit and social network that encourage authors or publishers to design their own rich-interactive content (e.g. books, magazine, brochure, etc.), publish and share with their friends or customers. Created the REST-based APIs to provide high-performance services for the entire business including content management, generation, conversion, storage and security. Developed online interactive editor and Android applications.

IriTech Inc. Seoul, South Korea

Senior Software Developer

2010 - 2012

Designed and developed cluster-based iris recognition services to accelerate iris matching speed to millions of comparison per second, enabled distributed shared memory and opened SOAP-based APIs for web and mobile applications. Developed visual toolkit to automatically detect memory leaks and evaluate the correctness of matching algorithm.

FPT Information System

Hanoi, Vietnam

Software Integration Engineer

2007 - 2008

Provided Sharepoint-based solution packages to the governmental organizations. Designed general Sharepoint workflows and enhanced annual report generating speed with MSSQL-BI cubes.

FPT Software Hanoi, Vietnam

Software Developer

2005 - 2007

Worked in Group 2 for software outsourcing, I participated in the task-force team working in the POC periods. My duty was solving technical problems, developed and tested for 6 outsourced software projects.

Technical and Personal skills

- **Programming Languages:** Java, C#, HTML/JavaScript, VB.NET, Matlab, C/C++, PHP, ASP, Erlang.
- o Software Skills: Android Studio, Eclipse, Visual Studio, SharePoint Services, Spring, Windows Workflow.
- o Platforms and Databases: Android, Linux, Windows Phone, MySQL, MS SQL-Server.

I share code at: http://www.github.com/minhld

Awards and Certificates

- o USU Graduate Research and Creative Opportunities, 2016
- o BK21 Scholarship 2008-2010
- o Microsoft Certified Application Developer, 2007
- o Bronze Prizes in National Mathematical Contest, 2001 and 2002

References

Young-Woo Kwon (Supervisor)

Tel: (435) 797-5508

Email: young.kwon@usu.edu